Joseph Osho

lagos, Lagos State • +2349134248820 • oshojoseph2@gmail.com • linkedin.com/in/joseph-osho-627211235 • www.twitter.com/graph_art_lawd • https://oshojoseph.onrender.com/

FULLSTACK DEVELOPER

5+ years of full-stack development experience in full-stack web and mobile applications with an emphasis on performance & security with Proven ability to collaborate with UX/UI designers and product managers to deliver solutions aligning with business goals and leading teams of developers in creating visually appealing and functional web and mobile applications to be Deployed on multiple hosting platforms and stores.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Lordwin Group • lagos • 11/2023 - Present

Tech developer of online games and bets

Full Stack Developer • Full-time

- Successfully developed a mobile application with five distinct theme modes, providing users with a diverse and personalized visual experience.
- Improved system performance by 40% through orchestrating a system of loosely coupled backend microservices in Nestjs, resulting in a more responsive and efficient gaming platform for smatvirtual.com
- Successfully tested and deployed microservices in Kubernetes clusters on AWS, Azure, Google Cloud, and Digital Ocean, and configured load balancers to expose them for external use, resulting in a 20% increase in system scalability and flexibility, leading to improved business agility and competitiveness.

Erranda · Lagos · 10/2023 - Present

A P2P Delivery system in Nigeria

Chief Technical Officer/Backend Devleoper • Full-time

- Created a functional backend to authenticate users with multiple roles and permissions for delivery agent, clients and admins
- Boosted user interaction by 40% with the successful setup of a Notification delivery system, resulting in higher user satisfaction and improved platform performance.
- Enabled secure Escrow payment system resulting in 30% increase in successful trades, boosting client trust and platform usage.

Impact Apps • lagos • 11/2023 - 01/2024

Tech application developing company

FULLSTACK DEVELOPER • Part-time

- Successfully implemented a cross-platform mobile application using React Native, showcasing versatility in iOS and Android development.
- Orchestrated the backend using Node.js, demonstrating proficiency in server-side JavaScript development.
- Integrated MongoDB to handle data storage and management efficiently, ensuring optimal performance and scalability.

- Implemented OAuth2 for secure and seamless user authentication for social accounts(twitter, Instagram,tiktok), prioritizing user privacy and data protection.
- Utilized Socket.IO to establish real-time communication, enabling dynamic updates and live interactions within the application.
- Demonstrated expertise in iOS development using Xcode, ensuring a polished and native-like user experience on Apple devices

Tech Workstations

A technological service devlepoment company.

Lead Frontend Developer

- Developed fully responsive landing page and waitlist submit form with validation for the Maeedits Platform app (https://maeedits.com)
- Developed fully responsive landing page and waitlist submit form with validation for the Bammby dating app (https://bammby.com)
- Modifying the Remedy Portal website and added a visually appealing CV page for resume rebrands (https://cv.remedyportal.com)
- Designed and developed The Hair-market e-commerce website using React framework https://hairmarket.ng
- Implemented mobile app features such as push notifications, Biometric and Google authentication, universal deep linking for Remedy app
- Conducted testing of beta app releases on both Android and IOS platforms, focusing on features and functionality
- Published compiled test and final build release version of application to both Android and IOS platforms
- Presented PRs for features done in the web and mobile applications for reviews and merge
- Integrated backend APIs with frontend for consumption and rendering of data
- Ensured seamless usage of data on the web browser by optimizing web page loading speed, reducing latency and improving data caching mechanisms
- Constructed a backup full stack web application for the Remedy CV page during server downtime
- Updated & modularised old code bases to modern development standards as part of slashing operational costs

Digibrand • lagos • 01/2020 - 06/2022

A web application development provider service

Fullstack Developer • Full-time

- Developed and deployed full-stack functional web applications for data processing, analysis, and visualization
- Spearheaded the creation of responsive and functional web applications
- Applied strategies to facilitate effective communication among team members, resulting in 25% increase productivity and team morale
- Setting up and deploying web applications on hosting platforms like Heroku and AWS
- · Managed timely updates to web applications, including content changes and database upgrades
- Created a real-time chat web application using Socket.io as a transport connection and Node.js as the backend
- Facilitated web3 wallet connection authentication to secure Ethereum Blockchain transactions
- Initiated an email notification system to keep users informed about website updates and news

EDUCATION

Higher National Diploma

Cloud Development • 09/2022 - 11/2022

End Web Development

University Of Science And Technology • 10/2021 - 12/2021

CERTIFICATIONS

Frontend Development with React • 10/2021 - 12/2021

University of Science and Technology Hong Kong

Cloud Development With AWS • 08/2022 - 11/2022

UDACITY/ALX

PROJECTS

Hairmarket.ng • 11/2022 - 04/2023

Robosys Labs

https://hairmarket.ng

Remedy Cv • 06/2023 - 07/2023

Robosys Labs

https://cv.remedyportal.com

Ayojagun • 05/2023 - 06/2023

Private Videographer

Portfolio Website for Videographer / Cinematographer

https://ayojagun.com

Remedy Portal • 06/2023 - 12/2023

Robosys Labs

https://remedyportal.com

Remedy Mobile • 06/2023 - 08/2023

Robosys Labs

Remedy mobile App on Google Play Store and App store

Bammby • 09/2023 - 09/2023

Robosys Labs

Responsive Landing Page and waitlist submit page for the Bammby Dating App

Maeedits Landing/Waitlist • 09/2023 - 09/2023

Maeedits

Dice.ng

Lordwin games

www.dice.ng

Erranda • 10/2023 - 03/2024

Erranda Tech

A Peer-to-Peer delivery system

https:/www.errandatech.com

smatvirtual • 01/2024 - 03/2024

Smat Virtual

A Gaming Company creating games for betting platforms

https://smatvirtual.com

SKILLS

App publishing, Bootstrap, Cascading Style Sheet, Cloud Development, Computer Graphics, DynamoDB, Excellent Communication, Firebase, Front End Web Development, Git, Hypertext Markup Language, JavaScript, Jira, Mobile Application Development, MongoDB, Monorepo, Next Js, Node.JS, NoSQL, Nx, PostgreSQL, ReactJS, React Native, React Native, Redux, Representational State Transfer, Socket.IO, Software Engineering, SQL, Tailwind CSS, Trello, Typescript, vue js, Web Application, Web Development, Zustand, Reading, Socializing